Here's how I ended up simplifying things. I'd love to see great testing ideas.
So, if you're particular to what you've created, post your solution to
the forums. I'm starting off refactoring things a little bit. What I'm
going to do is I'm going to add a function to get the location content values.
This will be useful when we actually try to use these tests for
some other things later on. And there we are. A function that'll
return location content values. I'm also going to pull the city name out so
we can use that for some validation steps later on. And there we are. It's now
inside of the function. And then we're simply going to call that function to
get our location content values and we can delete all those lines of code.
Now, all of these columns, as I said before, are not very important, so
we can delete them. And we can also null out the value in our query.
The next thing I want to do is actually fix this validation step. What we can do
is we can create a function that relies on the fact we can get the map and
set from our content values. And then we can simply iterate through those.
Then we can see if the values that we used to create the record actually past
the values in the cursor that are returned. Now, back to our task. So,
there's a lot of unnecessary code here now. All we have to do is call
validateCursor with our values and our cursor. All right. So now we've
converted the first test. We can do the same thing with the second test as well.
First of all, let's do the same abstraction we did before. Now, of course,
one of these values isn't going to be static, so we have to add that in.
So now we can say, content values equals getWeatherContentValues.
With our all important location row ID. Remember, our tables are linked.
And then we can insert it into the database. Query for it.
If the query is successful we can just call validateCursor again on our weather
values with our weather cursor. So much less code.
And that's it. Our test is vastly simplified and
it will be useful to us later on. So now we can try running this test again to
see if it still works after the refactoring. And there we are, test passed. Now,
it'd probably be useful for us to actually print out some more data so
we can see what was being tested. But, this simplification to our
test is going to help us as we move forward. We're not done with testing yet.